essentialwholesale.com 2013-12-17

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy

#### What information do we collect?

  * We collect information from you when you register on the Site, place an order, enter a contest or sweepstakes, respond to a survey or communication such as e-mail, or participate in another Site feature.
 
  * When ordering or registering, we may ask you for your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other information. You may, however, visit our Site anonymously but must register before placing an order.
 
  * We also collect information about gift recipients so that we can fulfill the gift purchase. The information we collect about gift recipients is not used for marketing purposes.
 
  * Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enhance your experience and gather information about visitors and visits to our websites. Please refer to the "Do we use 'cookies'?" section below for information about cookies and how we use them.
 
  * This Site is not directed at children under the age of 13, and we do not solicit or collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we are in possession of personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 13, we immediately delete such information. 

#### How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, purchase products, enter a contest or promotion, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other Site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize your Site experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.  

  * To allow us to better serve you in responding to your customer service requests.  

  * To quickly process your transactions.  

  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other Site feature.  

  * If you have opted-in to receive our e-mail newsletter, we may send you periodic e-mails. If you would no longer like to receive promotional e-mail from us, please refer to the "How can you opt-out, remove or modify information you have provided to us?" section below. If you have not opted-in to receive e-mail newsletters, you will not receive these e-mails. Visitors who register or participate in other Site features such as marketing programs and 'members-only' content will be given a choice whether they would like to be on our e-mail list and receive e-mail communications from us.
 
  * We may contract a third party vendor to distrubute our  promotional material on the internet. 

#### How do we protect visitor information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. When you place orders or access your personal information, we offer the use of a secure server. All sensitive/credit information you supply is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our databases to be only accessed as stated above.

#### Do we use "cookies"?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current Site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile and aggregate data about Site traffic and Site interaction so that we can offer better Site experiences and tools in the future.

We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our Site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

Third party vendors may use cookies to serve our  promotional material based on a users prior visit to [www.essentialwholesale.com](http://www.essentialwholesale.com/)

Users may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by  visiting the [Google Advertising Opt-Out Page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). Users may also opt-out of a third  party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)  opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your Site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders over the telephone by contacting customer service at (503) 722-7557.

#### Do we disclose the information we collect to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice, except as described below. The term "outside parties" does not include Essential Wholesale & Labs. It also does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or providing service to you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our Site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety.

#### How can you opt-out, remove or modify information you have provided to us?

To modify your e-mail subscriptions, please click on the “opt-out” link in the email communication. Please note that due to email production schedules you may receive emails already in production.

#### Third party links

In an attempt to provide you with increased value, we may include third party links on our Site. These linked sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our Site and welcome any feedback about these linked sites (including if a specific link does not work).

#### Changes to our policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this web page. Policy changes will apply only to information collected after the date of the change. 

#### Questions and feedback

We welcome your questions, comments, and concerns about privacy. Please send us any and all feedback pertaining to privacy, or any other issue at: Customerservice@ewlnatural.com

#### Online Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

#### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.

#### Your consent

By using our Site, you consent to our privacy policy.
